netiq.com 2017-07-05

# Privacy Policy - Company | Micro Focus

### 1\. Privacy Policy

This privacy policy describes how Micro Focus International plc and its group companies including Attachmate®, Borland®, NetIQ, Novell® and SUSE® ("Micro Focus") use your personal information. Your right to privacy is very important to Micro Focus. At Micro Focus, we believe that the personal information you provide to us must be kept confidential and used in a responsible fashion. We consistently strive to put our best efforts towards achieving both of these objectives. 

#### What information do we collect?

When you use this Website, please bear in mind that we may record: 

  * the areas of the Website that you visit; and 
  * information about your computer, such as which browser you are using, your network location, the type of connection you are using (e.g. broadband, ADSL etc) and your IP address.

We do this by using cookies (although the information we gather through our cookies is protected and remains anonymous so we cannot tell who you are). See our Cookie Policy below.

Once you register for membership, log in, or submit information through our Website we will know who you are and your activities on this Website and information about you and/or your company may be recorded on our systems. For example, we may ask for the following information when you sign up for membership of our specialist software support services or email news services, or when you buy products from us or register your products online:

  * your name; 
  * company name; 
  * email address; 
  * postal address; 
  * job function;
  * country where you are based or purchasing/registering our products from;
  * telephone number; 
  * your comments/questions; and 
  * the products/services you are interested in.

We may also collect personal information from you at trade shows/events, from telephone calls, surveys and/or other correspondence with you. 

If you make a purchase from us we may also ask for payment information such as the details of the payment card you are using to pay for any products/services. 

#### What do we do with the information we collect?

We use this information for a variety of reasons. The main reason we use this information is to provide you with the Website and our products and services (whether available via the Website or offline). We also use the information for: 

  * internal record keeping; 
  * product and service development; 
  * developing our Website; 
  * answering your queries or complaints; 
  * delivery of products or services and/or order fulfillment including through our resellers, distributors and other agents;
  * market research; and 
  * marketing our own products and services (including special offers and upgrades) to you. 

#### Marketing

We may send you information about Micro Focus' products and services or related data by post or email or telephone, unless you have asked us not to do so. 

If you are a customer of ours or you have previously asked us for information on our products and services, such as subscribing to our email news service, then we may send you information by email. However, in every marketing email message we send you we will give you the opportunity to unsubscribe from our mailings altogether. 

We do not provide your personal information to external organisations (i.e. outside of Micro Focus) for their own marketing purposes without your explicit consent. 

If at any time you do not want your information used for direct marketing purposes please contact us at [compliance@microfocus.com](mailto:compliance@microfocus.com) and if you decide that you no longer wish to receive marketing emails from us, please follow the unsubscribe link in one of our marketing email messages. 

However, please note that we may send out periodic emails, including to inform you of a technical service or security issues relating to a product or service you have requested or purchased, or confirming your request or purchase of a product or service. You will not be able to choose to unsubscribe from these communications, as they are considered an essential part of the service you have chosen. 

You can also easily manage and update your membership information at any time by logging onto your Micro Focus profile on our Website, including controlling whether you wish to receive marketing emails from us.

#### Who do we share this information with? 

Your personal information may be shared across the Micro Focus Group of companies. For example, your personal information may be processed by the relevant Micro Focus group company situated in the country in which you are accessing our Website from and the country in which you are purchasing our products/services, if different. Please bear in mind that the countries to which your personal information is sent/accessed from may have a different standard of data protection than the country in which you are situated. However, we have put in place protections to ensure that your information is safeguarded. To find out more information about the companies within the Micro Focus Group that may handle your personal information please visit [www.microfocus.com](http://www.microfocus.com/).

We may share your personal information with organisations acting on our behalf and with our manufacturers, agents, distributors or resellers, but they will only use the information to provide our products or services. However, any third party that we may share your information with must act in accordance with our instructions. We may also share your personal information with a purchaser or potential purchaser of our business. 

In some circumstances, we may have to disclose your personal information to comply with the law/other regulatory purposes, or because we are required to do so by a court, the police, or other regulatory body. 

#### How to get copies of or amend the information we have collected

You may request details of the personal information that we hold about you under data protection laws. If you would like a copy of the information held about you please write to us at [compliance@microfocus.com](mailto:compliance@microfocus.com). 

If you think any information we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, please email us as soon as possible. We will correct or update any information as soon as we can.

#### Security

Micro Focus takes security of your personal data seriously and in order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online, including policies on access to information and firewalls. However, despite the measures we take, we cannot guarantee the security of any personal information from third party 'hackers' illegally obtaining this information.

If at any point you suspect or become aware of a security incident (i.e. your password is stolen or you receive a suspicious communication from someone holding themselves out to be a Micro Focus employee or from a dupe website claiming to be affiliated with Micro Focus), please forward the communication to us or report the incident by email to [compliance@microfocus.com](mailto:compliance@microfocus.com) or in writing to Group Compliance Officer, Micro Focus, The Lawn, 22-30 Old Bath Road, Newbury, Berkshire, RG14 1QN, United Kingdom as soon as possible.

#### Linking to other websites

Our Website or marketing email messages sometimes include links to other websites which are not within our control. Once you have left our Website/marketing email message, we cannot be held responsible for the content of other websites or the protection and privacy of any information which you provide to those websites. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question. 

#### Safe Harbor Framework

Micro Focus complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Micro Focus certifies that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Micro Focus's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

* * *

### 2\. Cookie Policy 

This Cookie Policy applies to all of our Websites ("Websites").

By accessing any of our Websites, you agree that this Cookie Policy will apply whenever you access the Websites on any device.

Any changes to this policy will be posted here and we reserve the right to vary this policy from time to time and your continued use of our Websites after any such change has been posted will constitute your agreement to any such changes. 

#### Our Use of Cookies

Like many companies, some or all of our Websites may use "cookies". A Cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that is placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain websites. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. For more information on cookies, please see [www.whatarecookies.com](http://www.whatarecookies.com/).

Most of the cookies we use are "personalisation cookies" which are used to recognise repeat visitors to the Websites and "analytics cookies" which monitor how visitors use our Websites and give us a better understanding of what content visitors are spending most time reading. The types of cookies used on our Websites are as follows:

Cookie Type | Details  
---|---  
Strictly Necessary | These cookies are essential to enable you to receive a service on a website. For example, cookies to operate online shopping baskets, do your internet banking or to comply with the law (e.g. such as to keep your information safe).  
Analytics / Performance | These cookies are used only to help us to improve our Websites over time, by giving us insights into how the various sections of the Websites are used and how users interact with the Websites, for example which pages visitors go to most often and whether they get error messages from web pages. The information collected is anonymous and statistical.  
Authentication / Functionality | These cookies are used to identify unique visitors to the Websites. If you log in to the Websites, these are the cookies that allow us to remember who you are and what your preferences are so that we can provide you with access to pages personal to you, for example your account pages or your selected font size. These cookies help keep your visit to the site secure. These cookies can also enable enhanced, more personal features and to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video, which is how they are used on our Website. Whilst information collected by "functionality" cookies may or may not be anonymised, the "functionality" cookies on our Website only collect anonymous information.  
Targeting | These cookies collect information about your browsing habits to make advertising relevant to you and your interests. These cookies collect the most information about users.  
Session | 

These are cookies that are designed to ensure that your visits to the Websites are as smooth as possible. Their main uses are: 

  * Allowing us to identify your device as you use the Website, so that you are not treated as a new visitor each time you go to another part of the Website; 
  * Ensure that the servers that we use to power the Website each serve an equal number of users, to help make everyone's browsing as swift and responsible as possible;
  * Noting your browser's capabilities.

* * *

We have listed in the table below the specific cookies that we use and the purposes for which we use them. You will see that we have also identified whether they are session cookies or persistent cookies. 'Session cookie' is a commonly used description for a cookie which stores information about user page activities to allow users to be recognized within a website so any page changes or item or data selection is remembered from page to page; whilst 'persistent cookie' is a commonly used description for a cookie which helps websites remember your information and settings when you visit them in the future.

#### Type: Strictly Necessary

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent / Session | More Information  
---|---|---|---|---  
Java Session | JSESSIONID | This cookie is essential for the Java programming language to maintain a session with users. | Session | [http://stackoverflow.com/  
questions/595872/  
under-what-conditions-is-a-jsessionid-created](http://stackoverflow.com/questions/595872/under-what-conditions-is-a-jsessionid-created)  
PHP Session | PHPSESSID | This cookie is essential for the PHP programming language to maintain a session with users. | Session | 

[http://php.net/manual/en/  
function.session-id.php](http://php.net/manual/en/function.session-id.php)  
  
Access Manager | IPCZQX##########  
UrnNovellNidpClusterMemberId  
ZNPCQ003-########  
lb_esp  
lb_login  
lb_netiq  
lb_novell  
lb_partnernetprogram  
lb_suse | Access Manager is a Novell product used to manage authentication and security. These cookies are essential for its functionality. | Session | http://www.novell.com/  
support/kb  
/doc.php?id=7004090  
Access Manager | IPCZQX##########  
UrnNovellNidpClusterMemberId  
ZNPCQ003-########  
lb_esp  
lb_login  
lb_netiq  
lb_novell  
lb_partnernetprogram  
lb_suse | Access Manager is a Novell product used to manage authentication and security. These cookies are essential for its functionality. | Session | http://www.novell.com/  
support/kb/  
doc.php?id=7004090  
MyNetIQ Legacy | policytarget  
TJS | Legacy cookies used to manage access to restricted resources. | Session Persistent |    
  
#### Type: Analytics / Performance

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent / Session | More Information  
---|---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | AID  
APISID  
CAL  
GAPS  
HSID  
NID  
OGP  
OGPC  
PREF  
SAPISID  
SID  
SNID  
SSID  
__utma  
__utmb  
__utmt  
__utmv  
__utmx  
__utmxx  
__utmz  
_ga  
_gat | These cookies are used to collect anonymous information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile analytical reports which help us improve our Website. The cookies collect information such as the number of visitors to our Website, how they arrived there (e.g. directly from the internet or through linking from another website) and tracking which web pages they visited. | Persistent | 

[https://support.google.com  
/analytics/answer/6004245](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)  
  
Eloqua | BKUT  
ELOQUA  
ELQSTATUS | Eloqua Corp. is a marketing automation SaaS company owned by Oracle which developed automated marketing and demand generation software and services for business-to-business marketers. It is used for many core demand generation activities. | Persistent | 

[https://community.oracle.com  
/community/topliners  
/do-it/blog/2013/08/14  
/what-cookies-get-dropped-when-you-browse-to-an-eloqua-tracked-page](https://community.oracle.com/community/topliners/do-it/blog/2013/08/14/what-cookies-get-dropped-when-you-browse-to-an-eloqua-tracked-page)  
  
Double Click Tracking | _drt_  
id  
matchcasale  
matchfbx  
matchgoogle  
matchibehavior  
matchimprovedigital  
matchopenx  
matchpubmatic  
matchspotx  
matchtwitter  
wfivefivec | DoubleClick is a 3rd party product owned by Google that is used to measure campaign success. | Persistent | 

[https://www.doubleclick  
bygoogle.com](https://www.doubleclickbygoogle.com/)  
  
Decibel Insight | da_lid  
da_sid | Decibel Insight is a full suite of behavioral analysis tools. | Persistent | 

[https://www.decibelin  
sight.com/PrivacyPolicy/](https://www.decibelinsight.com/PrivacyPolicy/)  
  
#### Type: Authentication / Functionality

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent / Session | More Information  
---|---|---|---|---  
Language Preference | ag_language  
novell_language  
language  
user_language  
novell_lang_redirect_refer | Language cookie used to display content in users preferred language. | Persistent |   
Country Preference | user_country | Country cookie is used to display localized content based on a user's location. | Persistent |   
Novell Search | novell_search_type  
novell_search_paid_keyword  
novell_search_landing  
novell_search_campaign  
novell_search | Preserves search preferences on novell.com search. | Persistent |   
Home Page Banner Rotation | netiq_home_counter | This cookie is used to track the banner rotation count on the netiq.com home page. | Session | 

[https://www.decibelin  
sight.com/PrivacyPolicy/](https://www.decibelinsight.com/PrivacyPolicy/)  
  
Vbulletin Forums | bb_lastactivity   
bb_lastvisit | VBulletin is a 3rd party product used for forums and it uses these cookies to track visitor activity. | Persistent | 

[https://www.vbulletin.org/  
forum/portal.php](https://www.vbulletin.org/forum/portal.php)  
  
AddThis social sharing widget | __atuvc | Add This is a content sharing tool that allows users to share content on social media, blogs, websites, etc... | Persistent | 

[http://www.addthis.com/  
privacy/privacy-policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)  
  
LiveChat | __livechat  
__livechat_chat  
__livechat_lastvisit  
__lc  
visitor_id.#######  
km_ai  
km_lv  
km_uq  
mp_##############_mixpanel | LiveChat is an online marketing, live support and web analytics application for SMB and large enterprise offered in SaaS (software as a service) model. It is used to offer chat support to visitors of the site. | Persistent | 

[http://www.livechatinc.com/  
privacy-policy/](http://www.livechatinc.com/privacy-policy/)  
  
Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent / Session | More Information  
---|---|---|---|---  
DemandBase | s_fid | Used to deliver targeted personalization based on a user's location and known information about them. | Persistent |   
  
* * *

All information collected through the use of cookies is encrypted and we do not use cookies to collect information such as credit card numbers. 

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of all our Website features. For example, we use a cookie to remember your cookie preferences and so:

  * If you delete all of your cookies you will have to update your preferences with us again. 
  * If you use a different device, computer profile or browser you will have to tell us your preferences again. 

#### Web Beacons

Certain pages on our Websites may contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags or clear GIFs). These web beacons allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page and the information in cookies set by the third party.

#### IP Addresses 

An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our Websites, we may view the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. We use this information to determine the general physical location of the device and understand from what geographic regions our Website visitors come. We also may use this information to enhance our Websites. 

* * *

### 3\. Further Information and Complaints

Micro Focus takes its users' concerns seriously. If you believe that Micro Focus has not complied with this Privacy and Cookie Policy, or if you have any questions about our privacy practices in general, you may write to the Micro Focus Group Compliance Officer at the address provided below, or by email at: [compliance@microfocus.com](mailto:compliance@microfocus.com).

Micro Focus   
The Lawn   
22-30 Old Bath Road   
Newbury   
Berkshire, RG14 1QN   
United Kingdom

If you have a complaint, please describe in as much detail as possible the ways in which you believe that this Privacy and Cookie Policy has not been complied with. We will investigate your complaint promptly.

If you provide Micro Focus with inconsistent preferences (for example, by indicating on one occasion that you consent to our use of cookies and on another by declining cookies), Micro Focus will endeavour to update your privacy preferences in a timely and accurate manner. 

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, Micro Focus International plc and certain of its other UK group companies are individually registered as a 'Data Controller' on the public Register of Data Controllers as maintained by the UK's Information Commissioner. Micro Focus' overseas group companies process your personal data in accordance with data protection laws in the countries in which they operate. To find out more information about the companies within the Micro Focus group that may handle your personal information, please visit [www.microfocus.com](http://www.microfocus.com/).

We may change this Privacy and Cookie Policy from time to time by updating this page. Check this page from time to time to learn about any changes.

_This Privacy and Cookie Policy was last updated: 22nd February 2016_
